# **Harbir Jaura**

■ harbiri@gmail.com ② harbiri.github.io ♀ Toronto, ON, Canada ♀ harbiri

## **ABOUT ME**

I am a software developer who has recently transitioned from a career in Accounting/Finance. I have developed strong teamwork, attention to detail and problem solving skills through over 3 years of work experience. Fast and eager learner and excellent at defining business processes, documentation and integration of new software.

## EDUCATION

# University of Windsor 2021

**Bachelor of Computer Science** 

• Cumulative 92% average

# University of Waterloo 2016

Bachelor of Accounting and Financial Management – Honours Co-op

## **SKILLS**

LANGUAGES: Java, Python, C, Kotlin, SQL, HTML

**DESIGN:** Bootstrap, CSS, Photoshop

TOOLS/LIBRARIES: Git, Retrofit, Room, Anaconda

# PROJECTS

#### **CINEHUNT**

Android application for discovering movies that lets you filter by year, genre and popularity. Written in kotlin, leverages the retrofit library for API calls and published to the Google Play Store.

#### STOCK SCREENER

Stock screening application that features ability to view current price, historical data, and download financial information for any stock. Also features the ability to search for stocks by viewing top gainers/losers/most active stocks of the day.

#### **CHECKERS**

Checkers game written in Python with competent AI to play against.

## **EMPLOYMENT**

#### WHIRLPOOL CANADA

Credit Analyst

Mississauga, ON Nov. 2018 to Mar. 2020

- Oversaw a portfolio of Trade Partner accounts, along with analyzing and generating reports on the status of the accounts as well as probability of collection.
- Honed great negotiation skills through making payment arrangements with Trade Partners who have failed to pay within terms.
- Worked closely with the Sales team to improve payment terms and resolve deductions taken by the Trade partners.
- Implemented various process improvement projects including the integration of a large inventory financing organization.

#### ATS AUTOMATION

Junior Financial Analyst

Cambridge, ON Jan. 2017 to Nov. 2018

- Administered the building, maintaining and analysis of financial models and financial dashboards as a key part of the budgeting, forecasting and planning process.
- Routinely aggregated large amounts of data through reviewing and accurately consolidating various financial reports and presentations for key stakeholders within the company.
- Authored process improvements in the budgeting process through updated inputs in BPC software which directly boosted efficiency.
- Developed weekly sales outlook reports for use by senior leadership team as well as reconciliation between CRM software and financial reporting.

### SUN LIFE FINANCIAL

Waterloo, ON May 2016 to Aug. 2016

Junior Financial Analyst - Intern

• Assisted in monitoring and measuring performance against the budget and forecast. Developed exceptional problem-solving skills through monitoring, analyzing and resolving expense issues with internal business partners.

• Created and used budget and forecast templates for input into Hyperion.

## AWARDS

Dean's Honour Roll University of Windsor 2021

Merit Scholarship for academic excellence upon entry *University of Waterloo*